（アリババ）外に出ちまったのか？
（アラジン）見て。
Are we back outside?
Wait, look!
Then we're still...
それじゃあ　やっぱり　ここは…。
We're still inside the dungeon!
まだ迷宮の中だよ。
♪♪～
What happened?
（ジャミル）何が起こったんだ？
（モルジアナ）分かりません。
ドカッ！（蹴る音）
I don't know.
You incompetent fool!
うっ…。
（ジャミル）この能なしがぁ～！→
Don't you dare tell me you don't know!
分かりませんじゃねぇよ→
You worthless piece of trash!
このゴミクズが！
This is all your fault!
てめぇのせいだろ？　俺が
あんな平民にだまされるなんて。→
How could I have been fooled by some commoner brat?
くそぉ～～！
≪ノウナシガァ～！
Dammit!
Incompetent fool! Incompetent fool!
ノウナシガァ～！
All your fault! Incompetent fool!
てめぇのせいだろ
ノウナシガァ～～！
ひぃ～！
♪♪～
akogare wo ima tsukanda
My desires are within reach.
daikansei no namari ni
If the loud, welcoming cheers
kokochiyoku utaretanara
shoot home straight into your heart,
saa tobikomou
then come and jump in!
♪♪～
ashita kara umare kawaru toka
People say they'll change the next day.
dareka ga mikiri tsuketa toka
But they give up so easily.
kono machi no style toka
That's just how it is here.
sonna mono ni nagasare tsuzukete
They get swept away by those excuses day by day.
kado no toreta genseki ni ha
They're nothing more than a chip, swept off the edge
kitto daremo you ha nai
and no longer needed by anyone.
♪♪～
fushigi to tobira no mukou ni ha
Guess what? Out there,
v.i.p nanoru yatsu ha naku
no one's swaggering around like a VIP.
daremo ga kunou no hate sa ore mo
Everyone suffers their own heartaches, myself included.
akogare wo ima tsukanda
But my desires are within reach.
♪♪～
mi wo yudanereba ii  kaji ha kono te ni
Throw yourself in with abandon. I've got the wheel.
mitsu kazoete the show time
On the count of three, it's show time!
daikansei no namari ni
If the loud, welcoming cheers
kokochiyoku utaretanara
shoot home straight into your heart,
saa tobikomou
then come and jump in!
♪♪～
3rd Night
The World-
Creating Magicians
3rd Night
The World-
Creating Magicians
I can't see a single person down there.
人っ子一人いねぇ。
ここ　何なんだろうな？
What is this place?
ネクロポリス。
The necropolis.
Ugo told me about this place a long time ago.
昔　ウーゴくんから聞いたんだ。
「頑丈な部屋」の外には
死者の街　ネクロポリスが→
Outside the Room of Fortitude spreads the necropolis, the city of the dead.
広がってるって。
これって　そういう所なのかな？
I think this is what he was talking about.
The Room of Fortitude...
頑丈な部屋？　っていうか→
Wait, that giant can talk?
あの巨人　しゃべれんのか？
I can only bring out his body right now, but he definitely does have a head!
今は　体しか出せないけど
ちゃんと　お顔だってあるよ。
なかなか　ハンサムなんだ。
And he's pretty handsome too!
I bet. He's a great friend of yours, after all!
そっか。
お前の自慢の友達なんだな。
Why don't you introduce me to him after we get your flute back?
笛　取り返したら　ウーゴくん→
俺にも紹介してくれよ。
And I want to learn lots about you too, all right?
あと　お前のことも
いろいろ聞かせてくれよな。
Of course!
うん！　いいよ。
コツ　コツ　コツ　コツ…（足音）
≫コツ　コツ　コツ　コツ
ここが　ゴールなのか？
Is this the end?
俺たちが目指してきた　迷宮の。
ん？
Have we reached our goal?
ドン！
（２人）あっ！
うわっ！
うっ…　うわぁ～！
えっ？
ひどい…→
This is terrible. He has hideous burn wounds.
この人
前が　焼けただれちゃってるよ。
（心の声）≪この刺し傷は…≫
Those cuts...
はっ…　アラジン！
ん？
Aladdin!
ドカッ！
ドゴン！
ぐっ！
♪♪～
You bastard!
てめぇ！
（ジャミル）何なんだよ…。
ふざけんじゃねぇぞ　このゴミが。→
Don't mess with me... You piece of trash... You peasant!
下民が！　誰に口を利いてる…。
Who do you think you're speaking to?
ふん…　下民も領主も
ここまで来たら関係ねぇだろ。
In here, it doesn't matter whether you're peasant or a lord!
関係ない？
ふっ…。　ふざけんじゃねぇよ。
Doesn't matter?
Shut up.
弱くて
下品で　生きてる価値もない→
You weak, vulgar, worthless scum!
ゴミのくせによぉ！　はぁ～…。
≪はっ…　アラジンは？≫
Shoot, where's Aladdin?
あっ…　おい　待てよ！
Hey, wait!
ガキン！
待ちたまえ　君。　まだ　刑が→
Where do you think you're going?
You haven't received your punishment yet.
執行されていないじゃないか。
刑？
Punishment?
そうだ。　まったく…
何なんだよ？　あの化け物は！→
Yes, punishment! Seriously, what were those things?
Why did I of all people have to go through that?
なぜ　この僕が　あんな目に…。
全部　お前のせいだ！→
This is all your fault!
That's right! This is all your fault!
お前のせいだ～！
よっぽど
怖い目に遭ったみてぇだな。
Sounds like you had a pretty rough time.
But what are you crying about?
でもよ　今更　何　言ってんだ？
This is a dungeon.
ここは　迷宮だぜ？
Status, lineage, and reputation don't matter in here.
地位も　血筋も　名誉も関係ねぇ。
誰もが　人生懸けて　命張る場所。
This is a place where people put their lives on the line.
If you're scared, then cry about it at home, little man.
怖けりゃ　家で震えてな
お坊ちゃんよぉ！
（ジャミル）なっ！
Shut your mouth.
（ジャミル）もういい　黙れ。→
下民には　実力で
分からせねばならないようだな。
Lowlifes like you just don't get it unless it's beaten into you, huh?
≪バカが。　僕が　何年→
Idiot. He has no idea how long
I've been studying swordplay.
剣術を習ってきたかも知らず…。→
Royal swordplay, at that. It's only
meant to be taught to palace royalty.
しかも　本来は
王族にしか伝授されない→
王宮剣術だぞ。→
じっくりいたぶって　殺してやる≫
Slowly. I'll make you suffer slowly before I kill you.
（ジャミル）ふん！
まずは…　足！
ガキン！
First to go are your legs!
♪♪～
Lucky jump there.
よくよけたな。
だが　これは　どうだ!?
But where's your luck now?
Is this really all you've got?
こんなもんかい？　領主様。
くそっ！　くっ！→
Dammit!
なぜだ!?　なぜ当たらない!?
Dammit, why can't I hit you?
キン！
それはな…→
Because...
You have too many openings.
脇が開いてるからだよ。
うっ…。　うわっ！
首　肘　肩…→
Your neck, your elbow, your shoulder. They're all wide open.
がら空きだぞ。
先生に習わなかったのか？
Did you not learn anything from your instructor?
キン！
ううっ…。　あっ！
You get an "F" for failure.
落第点だぜ。
あぁ…。
≪ちょっと　剣術を
かじったくらいじゃ　こんな…≫
He isn't just some kid messing around with a blade.
≪これは　れっきとした…≫
He's the real deal...
（ジャミル）≪王宮剣術≫
This is real palace swordplay!
（ジャミル）お…　お前は　誰だ!?→
W-Who are you?
なぜ　トラン語が読める？→
Why can you read Toran?
何なんだ!?
What are you?
昔のことは　忘れたつもりなのに→
I wanted to forget about the past,
but I guess my body still remembers...
体は　覚えてんだな…。
くっ！　モ…　モルジアナ～！→
M-Morgiana!
今すぐ助けろ！　僕を助けろ～！
Save me! Save me right now!
無駄だぜ。
あんな遠くから…　あっ！
Quit your crying. She can't get over here—
キン！
この距離を　一瞬で！
くくっ。　どうした？→
How did you get all the way over here so fast?
What's wrong?
Do you finally understand now?
観念したのかな？　君～。
なあ　あんた　いつまで
こんなヤツに従ってんだ？
Hey, how long do you plan on obeying that jerk?
This is a dungeon!
ここは　迷宮なんだ。
領主様から逃げたって→
No one would blame you if you ditched him!
誰も　とがめやしねぇ。
You can be free!
自由になれるんだ。
M-Morgiana!
モ…　モルジアナ…。
うっ！
ドゴン！
≪な…　なんで…≫
Why?
♪♪～
はははっ…→
は～はははっ！　いい子だぞ。→
Good girl! You're my number one slave!
やっぱり
お前は　僕のいちばんの奴隷だ。
≪コツ　コツ　コツ
くっ…。
ぐわっ！
（ジャミル）この下民！　下民！→
You peasant scum!
Look at you, getting all cocky because you can swing a sword around!
ちょっと剣が使えたって　お前は
使われる側の人間なんだよ！
You're still nothing but a tool to be used, you trash!
You don't understand slavery at all.
奴隷ってもんが
全然　分かってない。
Take notes. This is how you use a slave.
見せてやるよ　正しい使い方を。
♪♪～
殺せ。→
Kill him.
ほら　僕の命令だよ？→
I order you to kill him.
できるだろう？　モルジアナ。
You can do it, can't you, Morgiana?
できるよな？　なあ？
You can, can't you?
Right?
♪♪～
Kill him.
（ジャミル）殺せ　殺せ→
殺せ　殺せ→
Kill him.
殺せ　殺せ…→
殺せ　殺せ→
Kill him!
殺せ～！
KILL HIM!
♪♪～
殺れ！
Do it!
はぁ　はぁ　はぁ　はぁ…。
くっ！
バキン！
あっ…。
えっ？
（ジャミル）何!?
What was that?
（ジャミル）
なんだ？　お前　何かしたのか？
Was that you? Did you do that?
♪♪～
ピィ　ピィ　ピィ…（ルフの声）
Are you all right, Alibaba?
アリババくん　大丈夫かい？
気をつけろ…→
Be careful.
あの女　やべぇぞ。
That girl is dangerous.
♪♪～
Give me back my flute.
僕の笛　返してよ。
（ジャミル）悪いね。
でも　こうでもしないと　君→
Sorry, but this is the only way to
keep you away from losers like him.
その小物ばかり　ひいきするだろ？
Give me back my flute.
僕の笛　返してよ。
なら　力ずくで　奪ってみろよ。
Why don't you try to get it back?
返して。　すぅ～…。
Give it back now.
♪♪～
あっ！
ピィ　ピィ　ピィ　ピィ…
なっ…。
くっ！
♪♪～
It's just like my teacher said it would be...
≪先生の言ったとおりだ。→
He's the one who will lead the king to greatness!
彼こそが　王を導く者≫
One of the all-mighty world-creating magicians!
≪偉大なる創世の魔法使い→
マギ！≫
A Magi!
ピィ　ピィ　ピィ　ピィ…
（家庭教師・回想）((坊ちゃん→
Young Master, shortly after my departure, the dungeons shall start to appear.
私が去ったすぐあと　迷宮が現れ→
１０年後　とある少年が
やってくるでしょう。→
After 10 years, a boy will also appear.
彼こそが…))
That boy...
Yes! You're here, the key to my
power, just like my teacher foretold!
≪いいぞ…。
君こそ　先生が予言した→
僕の力なんだな≫
♪♪～
（ジャミル）
マギよ　僕を選ぶと言うんだ。→
Magi, you are to choose me.
さもないと…。
If you do not...
モルジアナはね
あのファナリスの末裔なんだ。→
Did you know? Morgiana is a descendent of the Fanalis.
Her kick is like the thunder, capable of
cutting down anything that stands in its path.
その蹴りは　雷のごとく→
百獣の王ライオンの腹を
一撃で貫くという→
She has ripped apart a lion, king of the
beasts, with one stunning kick to its stomach.
まさに　地上最強の猛獣なんだ。→
She is truly the strongest beast.
さあ　マギよ→
Now, Magi,
if you do not want to end up like that lion,
君も　哀れなライオンに
なりたくなければ→
僕の軍門に下れ！
you will surrender yourself to me!
♪♪～
（ジャミル）えっ？　あっ…。
うっ…　くっ！
笛　返して。
My flute.
ま…　待ってくれ。→
W-Wait!
You're going to make me the king, right?
僕を　王にしてくれるんだろ？→
僕は待ってたんだ…→
I've been waiting for you!
I've been waiting for this day so I could be chosen by you!
君に選ばれる　今日という日を。→
That's the sole reason I've used people, laid down the law, increased trade, and turned Qishan into a prosperous city!
そのために　僕は
人を使い　法を敷き　商いを興し→
チーシャンを栄えさせた！
すごいだろう!?　そうだ…→
Isn't that amazing?
Aren't I amazing?
僕はすごい。
僕は偉い。　僕はできる男だ。→
I'm amazing. I'm capable of anything!
だから　僕を王様に…。
So make me the king!
王様？
King?
I don't know what you're talking about,
なんのことか分かんないけど
僕は　おにいさんのこと→
but I really don't think you're all that great, mister.
そんなに
大した人じゃないと思うよ。
あっ…　あぁ…。
大丈夫かい？　アリババくん。
Are you okay, Alibaba?
今の　すっげぇかったな！　魔法か？
What you did just now was amazing! Was that magic?
Seriously, what are you?
お前　ほんと　何なんだよ？
何って…
アリババくん　僕は　君の友達さ。
What do you mean, Alibaba? I'm your friend!
あっ…。
さあ　冒険の続きをしようよ。
Come, let's continue our adventure!
ゴールを目指そう。
ああ！
Let's not lose sight of our goal!
Yeah!
♪♪～
Who is the one who will be king?
（アモン）誰だ？　王になるのは。
♪♪～
（アモン）お前か？→
Is it you?
違う。　違うな。→
No, it is not.
Not you either.
Oh!
ぬっ？　これは…。→
It is... you!
お主。
えっ？
ふふっ！
な…　なんだ!?　今のは！　おい！
H-hey, what did you just say?
（アモン）
ぴいぴいしゃべるな。　聞こえんわ。
Stop yapping. I can't understand a word.
おい！　おい　おい！
（アモン）これはこれは→
Well, well, if it isn't a Magi.
マギよ。
えっ？
He bowed?
≪頭下げた？≫
Y-You!
（アモン）あ…　あなた様は…。
うむ。
（アモン）ふむふむ。
何を話してるんだろう？
I wonder what they're talking about.
通じてるのか？
（アモン）ふむ。→
I wonder if they even know what they're talking about.
大体の事情は　分かり申した。
I have a basic grasp of the situation now.
My name is Amon.
我が名は　アモン。
礼節と厳格から造られし→
I am the djinn of propriety and
discipline, and the master of flames.
炎をつかさどる　ジンです。→
この迷宮の主として→
As the ruler of this dungeon, I recognize the
two of you and declare this dungeon cleared!
迷宮クリアを認めます。
（２人）うわ～！
ク…　クリアか～！
C-Cleared? Yay!
うおぉ～～！
やあ　アモンくん。　僕は　アラジン。
Hi Amon.
I'm Aladdin. It's nice to... meet you, right?
はじめまして…　だよね？
Yes, this is our first meeting. But I already knew of you, Magi.
はい。　しかし→
私は
あなたを知っています　マギよ。
マギって　なんだい？
What's a Magi?
うむ…。
A Magi is someone who chooses the king.
マギとは　王の選定者。→
Every king is always chosen by a magician.
いつの世も
王は　魔法使いが選ぶもの。→
As long as there are people, there
will be a rightful king to lead them.
人が群れれば
正しく束ねる王がいる。→
And among the people, there will be one suitable of becoming the king.
王となるべき者がおる。→
その者を探し　見抜き→
We have been sent here for the sole purpose
of searching for that one person.
導いて　鍛えられる賢者を→
We must test, guide, and train that person.
我らが偉大なる大王は→
この世界に遣わされたのです。
And then there is the beloved one with Solomon's spirit.
愛しきソロモンの移し身よ。→
That is you.
それが　あなた様なのですよ。
♪♪～
Hey, since we cleared the dungeon, that
means we can take everything in it, right?
なあなあ　クリアってことは→
ぜ～んぶ
持ってっていいんだよな？　なっ？
Right?
（アモン）好きにせい。
うっひょ～！　ははは～！
Do as you please.
（アモン）はぁ…。
なぜ　あんな小僧にしたのですか？
Why did you pick a boy like him?
なんのことだい？
それより　ねえ　教えてよ。
What do you mean?
And furthermore, what do you mean by Solomon's spirit?
移し身って　どういうこと？
僕って　一体　何者なの？
What exactly am I?
うむ　それは…。
You are...
ドドーン！
ぬおっ!?
な…　なんだ!?
What's happening?
（アモン）何者かが
道を閉じようとしておる。→
Someone is trying to seal off the exit!
このままだと
外へ帰れなくなるぞ。
If he succeeds, we will no longer be able to leave this place!
あっ！
こ…　困るよ。　帰してくれよ～！
N-No way! Get us out of here!
（アモン）わめくな！
Stop your shouting.
帰る者は　この中に入れ。→
Those who wish to leave, step into this beam.
This dungeon is collapsing.
この迷宮は　崩壊する。→
取り残されれば　死ぬるのみだぞ。
Only death awaits those who are left behind.
おい！　お前は　戻らないのか!?
おねえさん　早く！
Hey, aren't you coming?
Miss, hurry!
なんで
そんなヤツ　気にかけるんだよ!?
Why are you worried about that jerk?
今まで　さんざん嫌なこと
されてきたんだろ!?
He's been nothing but terrible to you, hasn't he?
あっ　ゴルタス。　生きて…。
Goltas? You're alive.
（ゴルタス）こ…　こんな男…→
This man... cannot be allowed to leave.
出して…　ならない…。
しゃべれたの？
You can speak.
（ゴルタス）
こんな…　バカの言いなりに…→
I have done too much evil and have
killed too many people to leave this place.
人を…
たくさん　あやめてきた…。→
俺も　出るべきではない…。→
だが…　お前は違う。→
But you are different.
まだ戻れる…。
You can still return.
（ゴルタス）
国へ帰れ…　モルジアナ…。→
Return to your homeland, Morgiana.
That is my last wish.
それが…　俺の…→
最後の望み…。
あっ！
バキン！
♪♪～
送るぞ！
Ready to go!
♪♪～
ゴルタス　ドルジス　いい子だなぁ。
Good boy, Goltas...
よ～し　好きなだけ
トウモロコシをやるぞ。
I'll give you as much corn as you'd like.
あれ？　モルジアナは？
Wait, where's Morgiana?
♪♪～
Go now!
行くぞ！→
ソロモン王より授かりし魔力も→
This is the last vestige of the magic gifted by King Solomon!
これで最後じゃ。
ドドドド…
≫うわ～！
≪きゃあ～！
Are you okay with this, Magi?
（家庭教師）よいのか？　マギよ。
（ジュダル）うん。
Yeah. It'd be a pain if some weirdo cleared it.
変なのに攻略されたら面倒じゃん。
お前が種まいた　領主もいないし→
That's the end of your lord too. Let's get out of here.
もう帰ろうぜ。
♪♪～
クリア…　しちゃったね。
ああ。
We cleared it.
僕らの冒険も　おしまいなんだね。
And now our adventure is over.
♪♪～
俺はさ　この財宝を元手に→
I'm going to take this treasure and use it to start my own business in Sindria.
シンドリアで
ひと旗　揚げるつもりなんだ。
前に　絵巻　見せたろ？
I showed you a picture scroll of it before, right?
Sindria is the country that Sinbad created.
あのシンドバッドが造った国さ。
そこで　俺は→
TL note: "Sinbad's Dream" - a pleasure house with lots of beautiful women
I'm going to go there and make "Sinbad's Dream" a reality.
シンドバッド・ドリームを
実現させるんだ。
すてきだね。
まあ…　その前に→
That sounds great.
Before that, I have to stop by Balbadd to take care of some loose ends though.
ちょっと
バルバッドって国に寄って→
用事を済ませてからだけど。
What about you?
その…　お前は　どうすんだ？
う～ん　僕は別に…。
I don't really know.
そっか。
I see.
If I hadn't met you, I don't think I
would've been able to clear this dungeon.
俺　お前に会わなかったら→
攻略できなかった気がするよ。
つ～か　攻略にすら来なかったかも。
Actually, I don't think I would've even dared to try.
When the going gets tough, my legs freeze up,
いざとなると
足が　すくむっつ～か…。
and I fail miserably.
それで
ひでぇ失敗したこともあって。
まあ　単に　卑怯者とも言う。
I'm just a coward.
That's not true.
そんなことないよ。
君は　勇気ある人さ。
You're a really brave person.
砂漠のキャラバンを覚えてるかい？
Do you remember the caravan we were on?
君は　どれだけ　自分の夢や
名誉をバカにされても→
No matter how much others mocked
your dreams or even you as a person,
怒ったりしなかったよね。
you never got angry.
But when someone else's life was made light of,
けれど　ほかの人の命の価値が
バカにされたとき→
本気で怒り
自分の身を　投げ出すことを→
you didn't hesitate in your fury and didn't think twice about risking your own life.
ためらいもしなかったね。
Ever since that moment, I've been amazed by you.
僕　あのときからね→
君のことが　大好きになったんだ。
大丈夫。
君は　卑怯者なんかじゃないよ。
Don't worry. You're no coward.
You're a hero.
勇気ある人だよ　絶対に。
だって　君は
僕の尊敬する友達だからね！
You're my friend, and I think really highly of you!
L-Let's go together!
一緒に行こう！
何が　冒険は　おしまいだよ。
Don't say that our adventure is over.
There's still so much to explore out there!
世界には
もっと　ほかにも楽しいこと→
ワクワクすることが
いっぱいある。
まだ　なんにも終わってねぇよ。
Nothing's over yet!
Let's go and see the world!
だから　全部　見に行こうぜ。
なっ！　アラジン！
All right, Aladdin?
うん！
Okay!
Yes!
よ～し　決定な！
楽しみだな。
I'm so excited!
Let's go together, Alibaba!
一緒に行こうね　アリババくん。
約束だよ？
ああ。
It's a promise!
Yeah!
約束だよ。
It's a promise.
I'm... outside of the city.
ここは　郊外の…。
（どよめき）
（ブーデル）あの坊主が　攻略したのか!?
That kid cleared the dungeon?
≪迷宮の跡から…。
≪伝説どおりだぞ。
He appeared right where the dungeon used to be!
It's just like the legend said.
≪まさか　あいつが？
あっ…。
No way, did he really?
うおぉ～～！
（一同）おお～！
（一同）わあ～～！
すぐに　お前も来るよな。
You'll be here soon too, right?
I'll be waiting, Aladdin!
待ってるぜ　アラジン！
♪♪～
nozoite miyou
Take a look
yubi bouenkyou
through your finger telescope.
me ni mieru sekai ha subete kako no monogatari sa
The world you see before your eyes is a story already told.
♪♪～
kagayaku mirai wo miushinau na yo
Don't lose sight of the bright future ahead.
♪♪～
kimi ni ha motto ippai yume to kibou ga arun da
You're destined to realize great hopes and dreams.
bootto shitetara minogashichau zo
But if you blink for too long, they'll leave you behind.
♪♪～
dekinai riyuu sagasu yori
Instead of searching for an excuse,
yatte mireba ii
why not just give it a try?
♪♪～
nozoite miyou
Take a look
yubi bouenkyou
through your finger telescope.
yubi to yubi wo marume ryoume ni ate
Make circles with your fingers and put them around your eyes.
imeeji shite sagashiteru mono
Picture your hopes and dreams!
♪♪～
atama no naka no adobenchaaa
Picture your personal adventure story!
doko he mukau?
Where are you headed?
yubi bouenkyou
What can you see
♪♪～
yubi no sono sukima ni nani ga mieru?
in the space between your fingers?
tooi you demo hontou ha chikai
It might seem far, but it's really not.
yogen no you na takaramono
It's a promise as valuable as any treasure!
Child of the Rukh, are you awake?
Granny, do you know what I am?
Next time: The People of the Plains.
4th Night
The People
of the Plains
...hey, Aladdin, where did you go?!
（ババ）お目覚めかい？　ルフの子や。
おばあちゃん
僕が　何者か知ってるのかい？
って…
アラジン　どこ行ってんだよ!?
遠隔操作ウイルスによる犯罪予告
事件で、
警視庁は、逮捕した福岡市の男性
について、
誤認逮捕だったとして謝罪した。
今日午後、福岡市の男性の自宅を
訪れたのは